Atharva Thorkar

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER · BACKEND EXPERT

IIT Kharagpur 2024

■ 8010755422 | ■ atharvathorkar2002@gmail.com | • https://github.com/AtharvaT02 | • https://www.linkedin.com/in/atharva-thorkar-4a590b205/

Personal Profile

A Undergraduate student at the Indian Institute of Technology, Kharagpur. Zealous about software engineering and with 1+ years of experience specialising in Software development, python development, algorithms, cyber-security and full-stack web development. Primarily, looking for full-stack Developer/Python Developer roles.

Education

Indian Institute of Technology, Kharagpur

West Bengal, India

Aerospace Engineering

Dec 2020 - Current

• Courses: Programming and Data Structure, Machine Learning Foundation, NSOPDE,

Work Experience

Indian Institute of Technology

Indore, India

Software Engineer

Sept 2020 - Aug 2021

- Collaborated with a four-person team to develop a CNN model that utilised YOLO as a foundation to improve the accuracy of ambient lighting
 conditions in the Mobile net architecture.
- Automated and optimised the data handling process for traffic signs, working with Ubuntu 20.04 did shell scripting, and employed other Linux tools.
- Significantly boosted the model's accuracy by 60%, which was yielding an accuracy of 70-78% under Indian street light. The older models, had an accuracy of 10-15%.
- Technical Skills: Python with PyTorch, NumPy, Matplotlib, Pandas, Scikit-learn, C++, Ubuntu Linux, Linux tools, Apt, Scripting, Git.
- Soft Skills: Teamwork, Time Management, Communication, Presentation skills.

Raja Ramanna Centre for Advanced Technology

Indore, India

Machine Learning Intern

Apr 2020 - Sept 2020

- Build a model with a team of three that works with a Genetic algorithm and is portable for scheduling scenarios may it be a schedule for school, employee time sheet etc.
- · Designed to be flexible to any case with low time complexity compared to the existing models which were only useful in specific scenarios.
- Produced everything from scratch and published the library on PyPi.
- $\bullet \ \ \, \textbf{Technical Skills:} \ \, \textbf{Python with Genetic Algorithm, NumPy, Setuptools, Wheel, Twine, Git.} \\$
- Soft Skills: Leadership, Time Management, Communication, Logical Thinking.

University Projects

The Relation between GDP and IMR

Leeds, UK

University of Leeds

Feb 2022 - Apr 2022

- Analysing data from 1960 to 2020 and discover patterns in the data that show trends between Gross domestic product per capita, Infant Mortality
 rate, Literacy Rate, and Industrial Development.
- Study cross-sectional, longitudinal, and among various countries to find variations in trends and get the historical data to back up the change in the trend of our data.
- · Specific case studies were traced back to trends seen in the UK and how they affected the GDP and IMR.
- Technical Skills: Tableau, Overleaf, LaTeX.
- Soft Skills: Time Management, Teamwork, Presentation skills, Report writing.

IPL Analysis Leeds, UK

University of Leeds

Nov 2021 - Dec 2021

- Analysing data from 2008 to 2015 to discover patterns such as trends, correlations, and probabilities.
- · Finding the differences between the best teams and players in various fields, as well as their performance on the field and the opponents.
- Technical Skills: Python with Pandas, matplotlib, Seaborn.
- Soft Skills: Presentation skills, Leadership, Teamwork, Logical Thinking.

JANUARY 6, 2023

University of Leeds Oct 2021 - Dec 2021

• Study of serial killers behavior with various motives such as convenience (did not want children or spouse), enjoyment, power, escape, or avoiding arrest.

- Finding patterns in their starting and ending ages (when they are caught) and other factors of killing, as well as how it varies with different motives.
- Technical Skills: R with ggplot2, tidyr, R Markdown.
- Soft Skills: Report writing, Logical Thinking, Critical Thinking.

Skills

Programming Python (Pandas, PyTorch, NumPy, Scikit-learn. etc.), R(ggplot2), PHP, C/C++, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, SQL.

Miscellaneous Linux, Shell (Bash/Zsh), ™EX(Overleaf/R Markdown), Tableau, Microsoft Office, Firebase, Git.

Soft Skills Time Management, Teamwork, Problem-solving, Documentation, Engaging Presentation.

Achievements

| 2019 | 319/340 , Graduate Record Examinations (GRE) | India |
|------|---|-------|
| 2018 | Elite, DBMS NPTEL Exam | India |
| 2018 | Elite, C NPTEL Exam | India |
| 2019 | Winner, Smart India Hackathon (SIH) | India |
| 2014 | Level 3, TablaNiketan Exam | India |
| 2014 | Level 1, National Talent Search Exam (NTSE) | India |

Interests

Cooking I love cooking. I am an expert in most Indian-style cooking, enjoy baking and making my own pizza.

Linux Since 2017, I have been in love with Linux. I recently switched to Mac OS, which feels like a premium of Linux.

Technical Writing I write descriptive blogs about Linux some of them are on my GitHub and Medium.

Art I have always enjoyed drawing since I was a child. Recently, I have shifted to digital art mostly on Deviantart.

Video Games I always had the gaming gene. I mostly play on my phone and occasionally on my switch.

Swimming I started swimming when I was 12. Going through submerged things while holding my breath was the most exciting part.

Music I enjoy almost all types of music may it be screamo, punk rock, bluegrass, pop, psychedelic, rap, and japanese.

Languages

English Professional proficiencyHindi Native proficiencyBengali Bilingual proficiency